Finding Aid for Detroit Urban League 1916-1992
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- 1977 Accession
  - Detroit Urban League Files
    - Reference File
      - Surveys of Detroit Urban League 1943, 1949 (Box 71)
      - USO (Box 71)
      - Veterans (Box 71)
      - Vocational Services (Box 71)
      - Welfare, 2 folders (Box 71)
      - White House (Box 71)
      - Youth, 2 folders (Box 71)
      - Youth
        - Programs and Surveys, 3 folders (Box 72)
        - YWCA (Box 72)
    - Newspaper Clippings File
      - 1950-1959 (Box 72)
      - ADC (Box 72)
      - Adoptions (Box 72)
      - Detroit Board of Education (Box 72)
      - Detroit Community Relations (Box 72)
      - Detroit Politics (Box 72)
      - Detroit Programs and Policies (Box 72)
      - Discrimination (Box 72)
      - Editorials about Negroes (Box 72)
      - Education
        - General (Box 72)
        - Detroit and Michigan (Box 72)
      - Employment (Box 72)
      - Freedom March 1963 (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Negroes in Detroit (Box 72)
      - Negro Leaders (Box 72)
      - Race Relations (Box 72)
      - Religion (Box 72)
    - Green Pastures Camp File
      - Annual Report
        - 1954-1955, 2 folders (Box 72)
        - 1959-1960, 2 folders (Box 72)
        - 1964-1965, 2 folders (Box 72)
      - Handbook 1957 (Box 72)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 72)
- Sound recordings, 7 in. tapes unless indicated otherwise
  - Detroit Urban League Annual Dinner Meeting, Charles T. Fisher, III, speaker, "Detroit - The Challenge and the Promise", 1962 March 1962, Audio Reel-to-Reel
    - [Part 1], [851100-SR-1-1]; (Wednesday, March 14, 1962, 6:15 P.M. Detroit Urban League; Speaker: Charles T. Fisher, III; Subject: "Detroit - The Challenge and the Promise")
  - Interview with Francis A. Kornegay February 15, 1967, 7 1/2 ips (Box 73, Item 2)
    (Interview was part of WDTR program "A Time to Talk")
  - WDTR program "A Time to Talk" with guests Art Johnson, Jessie Kennedy, Francis Kornegay, and Horace Sheffield., 1967 February 09, Audio Reel-to-Reel
    - [Part 1], [851100-SR-3-1]; (WDTR program, "A Time to Talk" on the topic of "How effective is the strike as a new weapon in civil rights?" [with guests] Art Johnson, Jessie Kennedy, Francis Kornegay, and Horace Sheffield, recorded February 9, 1967)
  - Detroit Mayor Cavanagh speaking on WJLB program, "Crime Problem in Detroit" May 17, 1967, 00:28:08 min. (Box 73)
  - Francis A. Kornegay interview with June White October 8, 1967, 30 min. (Box 73, Item 5)
  - Action Programs (3) October 22, 1967, October 29, 1967, November 5, 1967 (Box 73, Item 6)
  - Lenore Romney interview with Tom Green April 4, 1967 (Box 73, Item 7)
    (secondary label indicates interview with Daniel Moynihan)
  - Combined reel, side 2 includes Urban League Leadership Council, "Crime and the Community" June 6, 1967 and 3 preparations for speeches in Los Angeles and Canton, Ohio, 1967-1968, 1 7/8 ips (Box 73, Item 8)
  - President's Cabinet Dinner, Cobo Hall. Bob Considine and Whitney Young discuss Detroit riots., 1968 March 18, Audio Reel-to-Reel
    - [Part 1], [851100-SR-9-1]; (Dinner and speeches discussing the Detroit Riot and its aftermath. President's Cabinet Dinner with Bob Considine as moderator, Whitney Young talks about Detroit riots and Fr. Carron comments. Broadcast on network week of March 18, 1968.)
  - Detroit Urban League, Sunday April 20, 1969 (Box 73, Item 11)
  - Francis A. Kornegay speaks after presenting check for $5000 to U-M President Robben Fleming for the Martin Luther King Memorial Fund June 26, 1969, 5 in. tape; 00:07:20 min. (Box 73, Item 12)
  - "Crime / Urban League" speaker Aubrey March 8, 1970, 5 in. tape: 00:13:22 min. (Box 73, Item 13)
  - Francis A. Kornegay interview with a former ADC mother May 31, 1970 (Box 73, Item 14)
  - WCHD program with Francis A. Kornegay October 25, 1970 (Box 73, Item 15)
  - 1970 tape sent to FAK of talk by Jim Turner, a Vietnam War veteran, speaking before the Dancy Adult Day School (or a Wayne State University psychology class) (Box 73, Item 16)
  - Francis A. Kornegay speaks after presenting gift to University of Michigan for the Martin Luther King Memorial Fund., 1969 June 26, Audio Reel-to-Reel
    - [Part 1], [851100-SR-12-1]; (Francis A. Kornegay discussing African American education at the University of Michigan after presenting check for $5000 to University of Michigan President Robben Fleming for the Martin Luther King Memorial Fund.)
  - Undated in two parts, 2 tapes (Box 73, Item 18)
    (penciled index includes topics as UL philosophy, "Uncle Tom" definition, Negro businesses, etc.)
  - Remarks and introduction by Thomas S. Nurnberger followed by address of William Haber, [Undated], Audio Reel-to-Reel
    - [Part 1], [851100-SR-20-1]; (Remarks by Thomas S. Nurnberger, Frank J. Armstrong, Dr. William Haber.)
  - Undated, unidentified with "12th Street Incident" on box cover (Box 73, Item 20)
  - Undated, "Youth Conference" (Box 73, Item 21)
  - Undated, "Whitney Young #2" (Box 73, Item 22)
  - Undated, Urban League Program 2-3 (Box 73, Item 23)
  - Undated, Urban League Program 4-5 (Box 73, Item 24)
  - Undated, Urban League Program 8 summary (Box 73, Item 25)
  - Unidentified, 2 tapes (Box 73, Item 26)
- 1985 Accession
  boxes 74-87
  In the summer of 1985, the Detroit Urban League added materials to its holdings at the Michigan Historical Collections. These materials, comprising thirteen linear feet of records, document the later 1960s and the 1970s, although there are some materials dating as early as 1926. The materials are especially strong in documenting the activities of the D.U.L. in the early 1970s. They have not been interfiled with earlier records. Thus, there may be considerable overlap with documents arranged in the earlier accessions.
  - Executive Directors' Files
    Material from the 1985 accession is divided into three subgroups to parallel the tenure of the executive directors: John C. Dancy, 1918-1960; Francis A. Kornegay, 1960-1978; and Roy L[evy] Williams, 1978-1984. Within the three subgroups, materials have been arranged according to office of creation within the D.U.L. hierarchy: Executive Board, Executive Director (changed to President in 1978), Assistant (Deputy) Director, and Departments (Committees during Dancy's tenure) arranged alphabetically. Within these series, the materials are first arranged according to type and then chronologically. They include correspondence, minutes, reports, memoranda, and topical files created by the D.U.L. The best sources to gain a sense of D.U.L. activity are the executive board minutes; the richest sources on the condition of Blacks in Detroit are the various departmental research reports.
    - John C. Dancy 1926-1967
      (primarily 1944-1960)
      - Negro Church in Michigan circa 1926
        - Negro Population of Detroit (Dancy) circa 1930 (Box 74)
        - Negro in Michigan (Dancy) 1933 (Box 74)
        - Observations on Conditions among Negroes (W. Banner) 1941 (Box 74)
        - Urban League Analysis (F. Washington) 1944 (Box 74)
        - Compiled historical materials and notes circa 1967 (Box 74)
      - Executive Board 1939-1960
        - Annual Reports 1944-1960 (Box 74)
          (incomplete)
        - Bylaws and Constitutions circa 1945-1955 (Box 74)
        - Committees 1944-1960
          - Budget and Finance 1952-1960 (Box 74)
          - Budget and Finance: Community Chest Reports 1944-1956 (Box 74)
        - Correspondence 1939-1960, 3 folders (Box 74)
        - Minutes 1948-1960, 4 folders (Box 74)
      - Executive Director, John Dancy 1931-1967, 1948-1960
        - Correspondence 1931-1967, 8 folders (Box 74)
        - Topical File, 1957-1960
          - Administrative Assistant (Valentine) 1944-1946 (Box 74)
          - Anderson, Marion (appearance) 1958 (Box 74)
          - Booker T. Washington Trade Association 1942-1949 (Box 74)
          - Group Work Monthly Reports 1944-1945 (Box 74)
          - Guild 1952-1959 (Box 74)
          - Jones, Eugene Kinkle - correspondence 1939-1950 (Box 74)
          - Miscellaneous 1939-1955 (Box 74)
          - Student Aid and Scholarships 1937-1960
            - Accounts and Budgets 1940-1960 (Box 74)
            - Correspondence 1937-1955, 2 folders (Box 74)
            - United Negro College Fund 1950-1951 (Box 74)
      - Standing Committees and Departments 1945-1960
        - Community Services 1947-1959
          - Adoption Agencies 1954-1959 (Box 74)
          - Monthly Reports and Prospectus 1947-1948 (Box 74)
          - Research Reports 1954-1959 (Box 74)
        - Membership 1945-1949 (Box 74)
        - Public Relations 1945-1960 (Box 74)
        - Vocational Services 1947-1960
          - Annual and Monthly Reports 1947-1960 (Box 74)
          - Research Reports 1958-1959
            - Men's Clothing Store Survey 1958-1959 (Box 74)
            - Police Hiring 1958 (Box 74)
          - Statement on training and employment 1960 (Box 74)
      - Temporary Committees 1944-1960
        - Citizens Advisory Committee on School Needs 1957 (Box 75)
        - Citizens Survey Committee 1948
          - Financing; Social Welfare Planning (T. Hunter) 1948 (Box 75)
          - Leisure time under government auspices (W. Batchelor) 1948 (Box 75)
          - Settlements and Community Centers (W. Brueckner) 1948 (Box 75)
        - Hospitals and Medical Services 1946-1960, 2 folders (Box 75)
        - Housing Survey (Dancy) 1944 (Box 75)
        - Tenth Police District Citizens' Attitudes on Crime (W. Price) 1959 (Box 75)
    - Francis A. Kornegay 1951-1978, 1960-1978
      - Executive Board 1960-1978
        - Annual Reports 1960-1976, 2 folders (Box 75)
        - Bylaws and Constitution 1970-1978 (Box 75)
        - Committees 1960-1978
          - Budgets and Finance 1962-1978, 8 folders (Box 75)
          - Camps, Education, and Youth Incentives 1964 (Box 75)
          - Education Task Force 1971-1976, 2 folders (Box 75)
          - Executive Committee 1961-1977, 3 folders (Box 75)
          - Executive Council 1975-1978 (Box 75)
          - Job Development and Employment 1964-1965 (Box 75)
          - Nominating 1960-1978 (Box 75)
          - Personnel 1969-1978, 2 folders (Box 75)
          - Program Planning and Research 1964-1978, 2 folders (Box 75)
          - Treasurer 1962-1978, 3 folders (Box 75)
        - Correspondence 1961-1978, 6 folders (Box 75)
        - Minutes and Agendas 1961-1978
          - 1961-1967, 7 folders (Box 75)
          - 1968-1978, 11 folders (Box 76)
        - Correspondence
          - 1959-1971, 26 folders (Box 76)
          - 1972-1978, 40 folders (Box 77)
        - General Files, (Kornegay's Office Files) 1955-1971
          (primarily 1962-1968)
          - Administration Conferences 1962-1963 (Box 78)
          - Citizens Advisory Committee on School Finance 1965-1966 (Box 78)
          - Citizens' Campaign Task Force Against Crime 1969 (Box 78)
          - Demonstration City 1965-1966 (Box 78)
          - Departmental Prospecti 1966 (Box 78)
          - Detroit Riot 1967, 2 folders (Box 78)
          - Educational Equal Opportunity 1960-1964 (Box 78)
          - First Federal Management Corp. 1967-1968 (Box 78)
          - First Federal Savings and Loan 1963-1965 (Box 78)
          - Ford, Henry 1967 (Box 78)
          - General Motors 1960-1971 (Box 78)
          - Greater Opportunity Industrialization Center 1963 (Box 78)
          - Guild 1967-1968 (Box 78)
          - Home Federal Savings and Loan 1955-1969 (Box 78)
          - Housing Department Problem Assessment (G. King) 1967 (Box 78)
          - Middle Class Negro 1967-1968 (Box 78)
          - New Detroit Committee 1967-1968 (Box 78)
          - Non-White City Employees 1963-1965 (Box 78)
          - Poverty Projects 1964 (Box 78)
          - Research Seminars 1966-1967 (Box 78)
          - Scholarship Committee 1967-1968 (Box 78)
          - Social Hygiene Forum 1964 (Box 78)
          - Speeches on Race Relations 1961-1969 (Box 78)
          - Staff Meetings Minutes 1960-1969 (Box 78)
          - Staff Memoranda 1962-1969 (Box 78)
          - Survey of Attitudes of Detroit Negroes after the Riot 1967-1968 (Box 78)
          - Total Action Against Poverty 1967-1968 (Box 78)
          - Unionizing the D.U.L. 1968-1970, 2 folders (Box 78)
          - Veterans Affairs 1967-1970, 2 folders (Box 78)
          - Voter Registration 1964 (Box 78)
          - Westside Task Force 1967 (Box 78)
          - WJR Radio Broadcasts 1967-1970 (Box 78)
          - Young, Whitney 1961-1963 (Box 78)
        - 1971 Annual Files 1970-1972
          - Abortion 1970-1972 (Box 79)
          - Blood Pressure Demonstration 1972 (Box 79)
          - Census Project 1970 (Box 79)
          - Education 1970 (Box 79)
          - Kornegay Memos 1970 (Box 79)
          - Model Neighborhood 1970-1972 (Box 79)
          - New Thrust 1970-1972 (Box 79)
          - Police Officers Recruitment 1971-1972 (Box 79)
          - Staff Reports 1971 (Box 79)
          - University of Michigan - Black Living Units 1971-1972 (Box 79)
          - Welfare Study Commission 1970 (Box 79)
        - 1972 Annual Files 1970-1974
          - A.F.S.C.M.E. 1972 (Box 79)
          - Golden State Mutual Life Insurance 1970-1972 (Box 79)
          - Greer, Clarence 1971-1972 (Box 79)
          - Guild 1971-1974 (Box 79)
          - Home Federal Savings 1971 (Box 79)
          - Metropolitan Fund, Inc 1973-1973 (Box 79)
          - New Detroit 1972-1973 (Box 79)
          - Police Proposal 1971-1972 (Box 79)
          - Quota System 1972 (Box 79)
          - Roth's decision on Bradley v. Milliken 1970-1974 (Box 79)
          - United Community Services 1972-1973 (Box 79)
        - 1973 Annual Files 1972-1975
          - Ad hoc leadership group 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - Burton Mercy Hospital 1973-1975 (Box 79)
          - D.U.L./MESC Memoranda of Understanding 1973 (Box 79)
          - Economic Club of Detroit 1972-1974 (Box 79)
          - Elected Officials Compensation 1972-1974 (Box 79)
          - Hypertension Spot Check Program 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - "Keep Detroit Beautiful," Inc. 1973 (Box 79)
          - Media 1973 (Box 79)
          - Minority Employment Hospital Survey 1973 (Box 79)
          - Personnel Revisions Committee 1973 (Box 79)
          - Virginia Park Citizens 1973 (Box 79)
        - 1974 Annual Files 1972-1975
          - Citizens' Campaign Against Crime 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - Coalition to end discrimination in housing 1974 (Box 79)
          - Department Heads Meetings 1971-1974 (Box 79)
          - Education Task Force 1972-1974 (Box 79)
          - Ford Motor Company 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - Independent Ministers Alliance 1974 (Box 79)
          - Intergroup Community Services, - Youth Leadership 1974-1975 (Box 79)
          - Media Survey 1973 (Box 79)
          - Narcotics Addiction Rehabilitation Coordinating Organization 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - New Thrust (weekly reports) 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - On the Job Training program 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - Opportunities Industrialization Center 1974 (Box 79)
          - Public Issues Task Force 1972-1975 (Box 79)
          - Radio Notes 1973-1974 (Box 79)
          - Residency and Accountability 1974 (Box 79)
          - Twelfth Street Academy Evaluation 1972-1973 (Box 79)
          - Vocational Services Task Force 1972-1973 (Box 79)
        - 1975 Annual Files 1972-1977
          - Annotated highlights of Department meetings 1974 (Box 80)
          - Citizens' Campaign Against Crime 1975 (Box 80)
          - Council on Health Affairs of Medical Community 1975 (Box 80)
          - Detroit Plan, Affirmative Action for Building Trades 1975 (Box 80)
          - Detroit School Desegregation 1975-1976 (Box 80)
          - Education Task Force 1975 (Box 80)
          - Food Market Survey 1975-1977 (Box 80)
          - Health Happenings 1975 (Box 80)
          - Health/Welfare Task Force 1975 (Box 80)
          - Hypertension Planning Committee 1975 (Box 80)
          - King, Martin Luther, Housing Corporation 1972-1976 (Box 80)
          - Michigan HMO Plans 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 80)
          - Nutrition Education 1975-1976 (Box 80)
          - Radio Broadcasts 1975-1976 (Box 80)
          - Staff Happenings 1975 (Box 80)
          - Study Committee (Booz-Allen Report) 1974-1976 (Box 80)
          - United Community Services 1975 (Box 80)
          - United Foundation 1975-1976 (Box 80)
        - 1976 Annual Files 1973-1977
          - "Equal Opportunity: Mandate and Challenge," 1977 (Box 80)
          - Food Stamp Conference 1976 (Box 80)
          - Greater Opportunity Industrial Center 1973-1977 (Box 80)
          - H.E.W. 1977 (Box 80)
          - Humanities Proposal 1976-1977 (Box 80)
          - Management by Objective Goals 1976 (Box 80)
          - Public Hearing on SEMTA 1976 (Box 80)
          - Public Issues Task Force 1975-1977 (Box 80)
          - Public Transportation Council 1976-1978 (Box 80)
          - ROTC Project No. 2 1976-1978 (Box 80)
          - Study Committee (Booz-Allen Report) 1975-1976 (Box 80)
          - United Community Services 1976 (Box 80)
          - Voter Registration 1976 (Box 80)
        - Michigan Council of Urban Leagues 1970-1978, 4 folders (Box 80)
        - National Urban League 1971-1977, 4 folders (Box 81)
        - Personnel Files 1965-1977
          - Aldridge, Lorraine 1972-1974 (Box 81)
          - Banks, Joseph M. 1972-1975 (Box 81)
          - Bowen, Toni 1972-1974 (Box 81)
          - Brame, Walter M. 1975-1976 (Box 81)
          - Estes, William E. 1975 (Box 81)
          - Fermiole, Richard 1968-1969 (Box 81)
          - Jones, Lovell E. 1965-1966 (Box 81)
          - Kelly, Margurite R. 1975-1976 (Box 81)
          - Lang, Winston E. 1969-1974 (Box 81)
          - McGlothian, Dr. Odell 1984 (Box 81)
          - Mitchell, Toni 1973-1974 (Box 81)
          - Smith, Lucille 1975-1977 (Box 81)
          - Taylor, Richard 1973-1974 (Box 81)
          - Tucker, Thomas 1974 (Box 81)
          - Vaughn, George L. 1974-1977 (Box 81)
          - Whitten, Eloise 1965 (Box 81)
          - Williams, Roy L. 1965-1968 (Box 81)
          - Wilson, William N. 1968 (Box 81)
      - Deputy Director, Winston Lang 1967-1978
        - Correspondence 1967-1978, 4 folders (Box 81)
        - Memoranda 1969-1976, 7 folders (Box 81)
        - Minutes 1969-1974, 3 folders (Box 82)
        - Proposals 1967-1973, 3 folders (Box 82)
        - Reports 1969-1978
          - Annual and Quarterly 1969-1974, 5 folders (Box 82)
          - Weekly 1972-1978, 6 folders (Box 82)
            (missing 1975-1976)
      - Departments 1947-1978
        (primarily 1968-1978)
        - Communications 1947-1978
          (primarily 1969-1978)
          - Memoranda 1972-1973 (Box 82)
          - Newsletters 1947-1978, 2 folders (Box 82)
          - Press Releases 1969-1978, 9 folders (Box 82)
          - Reports, Quarterly 1973-1978, 2 folders (Box 82)
          - Staff Happenings 1970-1978, 2 folders (Box 82)
      - Departments 1947-1978
        - Educational Services 1962-1978
          (primarily 1972-1978)
          - Butzel-Stevens-Pope scholarship 1963-1978, 2 folders (Box 83)
          - Education Task Force 1972-1978, 4 folders (Box 83)
          - Memoranda 1974-1978, 2 folders (Box 83)
          - Projects 1964-1974
            - Back to School 1974 (Box 83)
            - East City 1973-1974 (Box 83)
            - Low Achievers (Dr. Wurtz) 1974 (Box 83)
            - School/Community (Kennedy) 1974 (Box 83)
            - Tutorial 1964-1968 (Box 83)
          - Reports, Quarterly 1973-1978, 5 folders (Box 83)
          - Topical 1962-1978
            - Coalition for Peaceful Integration 1975-1978 (Box 83)
            - Decentralization - Detroit Public Schools 1968-1971 (Box 83)
            - Desegregation - Detroit Public Schools 1973-1976 (Box 83)
            - Detroit Middle School Survey 1978 (Box 83)
            - Drop Out Program 1962-1974 (Box 83)
            - Education/Youth Incentive 1967-1969 (Box 83)
            - Literacy Volunteers of America 1976 (Box 83)
            - Miscellaneous undated (Box 83)
            - Parents' Seminar 1963 (Box 83)
            - Radio-TV Task Force 1974 (Box 83)
          - Twelfth Street Academy 1968-1976
            - Advisory Council 1972-1974 (Box 83)
            - Memoranda 1970-1972 (Box 83)
            - Miscellaneous 1970-1974 (Box 83)
            - Reports, Quarterly and Weekly 1968-1976, 4 folders (Box 83)
            - Staff Meetings 1973-1975 (Box 83)
        - Housing 1963-1967
          - Committee on Relocation Advising 1963-1967 (Box 84)
          - Minutes 1963-1964 (Box 84)
          - Projects 1964-1967
            - Elmwood Park no. 2 1966 (Box 84)
            - Kenilworth Courts 1966 (Box 84)
            - Neighborhood Clubs 1964-1967 (Box 84)
            - Neighborhood Fair Practices 1966 (Box 84)
          - Reports, Quarterly 1964-1967 (Box 84)
        - Intergroup Community Services (Administrative) 1974-1979
          - Director's Files 1975-1976 (Box 84)
          - Minutes 1974-1976, 2 folders (Box 84)
          - Procedure Manuals 1974-1975 (Box 84)
          - Program Description 1974 (Box 84)
          - Reports, Quarterly 1974-1978, 4 folders (Box 84)
          - Topical 1974-1979
            - Consumerism 1975-1979 (Box 84)
            - Near Westside Forum 1976 (Box 84)
            - Voter Registration 1976 (Box 84)
            - Youth Leadership Development 1974-1975 (Box 84)
        - Intergroup Community Services (Divisions) 1974-1978
          - Criminal Justice 1974-1975, 2 folders (Box 84)
          - Health 1975-1976, 2 folders (Box 84)
          - Housing 1974-1978, 3 folders (Box 84)
          - Welfare 1974-1977, 3 folders (Box 84)
        - Religious Resources 1962-1968
          - Correspondence 1962-1968 (Box 84)
          - Minutes 1962-1964 (Box 84)
          - Workshop 1962-1964, 3 folders (Box 84)
        - Research and Information Services 1951-1975
          (primarily 1964-1975)
          - Administration 1964-1971, 2 folders (Box 85)
          - Reports 1951-1975
            - Health and Welfare 1959-1975 (Box 85)
            - Housing 1951-1965 (Box 85)
            - New Detroit 1974 (Box 85)
            - New Thrust 1968-1969 (Box 85)
            - Vocational Services 1961-1973 (Box 85)
        - Vocational Services
          - Correspondence 1961-1972, 2 folders (Box 85)
          - Memoranda 1966-1977, 5 folders (Box 85)
          - Minutes 1965-1977, 2 folders (Box 85)
          - Program Prospecti 1961-1972 (Box 85)
          - Reports 1965-1978
            - Annual 1971-1976 (Box 85)
            - Quarterly 1965-1978, 12 folders (Box 85)
            - Special 1965-1969 (Box 85)
            - Weekly 1972-1975 (Box 85)
          - Task Force 1974-1978 (Box 85)
  - President's Files
    - Williams, Roy L. 1978-1986
      (Primarily 1978-1982)
      - Executive Board 1979-1983
        - Minutes 1979-1983, 4 folders (Box 86)
      - President, Roy L. Williams 1978-1982
        - Correspondence 1978-1981, 7 folders (Box 86)
        - Office Chronological File 1980-1981, 6 folders (Box 86)
        - Topical Files 1978-1982
          - Beulah Land, TV Program 1980 (Box 86)
          - Coalition 1982 (Box 86)
          - Community Origins of Five Detroit Hospitals 1980 (Box 86)
          - Fixing the Victim 1980 (Box 86)
          - Parent-Child Center 1979 (Box 86)
          - Programmatic Implications of Goals 1979 (Box 86)
          - Public Issues Task Force 1978-1982 (Box 86)
      - Executive Assistant to President 1978-1986
        - Blue Monday Network 1978-1982, 2 folders (Box 86)
        - Distinguished Warriors 1980-1986, 2 folders (Box 86)
        - D.U.L. Briefs 1979-1980, 2 folders (Box 86)
  - Photographs and Visual Images 1918-1985